Many tasks are impossible to solve without machine learning.
機械学習がなければ 多くのタスクを解決できません
But let's take a step back for a moment and see how you would
仮に 機械学習モデルなしで
classify these images without a machine learning model.
いくつかの画像を分類する方法を 考えてみましょう
So if we were to write an algorithm to classify
画像を分類するアルゴリズム たとえば
what are some things we might look for?
どんな事を基準に分けますか？
If you thought about color, you're on the right track.
「色」がふさわしいですね
So we could look at the color of the pixels and image.
画像のピクセルの色を調べます
If the majority of the pixels in the image are red,
ピクセルの大部分が赤であれば
we would output apple is the classification.
分類の出力は たとえば「リンゴ」です
If the majority of the pixels were orange,
ピクセルの大部分がオレンジ色なら
we would output orange.
出力は「オレンジ」です
This would work really well in this example.
この例ではうまくいきますね
But what if the images were varied slightly?
でも 画像が少しずつ違ったら？
What if we had gray scale images?
グレースケールだったら？
Then we would need to look for a different feature.
別の特徴を調べる必要があります
Maybe the presence of a stem or the texture of the image.
たとえば 茎があるか 画像の質感はどうか
So we need to start writing our algorithm again to
それで 正確に分類するために
output accurate classification for these images.
再びアルゴリズムを書き始る必要があります
What if we added a mango? You get the idea.
マンゴーが加わったら？ そうです
Then we'd have to start our classification algorithm all over again.
分類アルゴリズムをまた最初から始めるのです
But these images are all pretty similar.
でも これらの画像はどれも似ています
They're all circular. They're all fruits.
すべて円形の果物です
So if we had two images that we wanted to classify that looks nothing alike,
では まったく似ていない 2枚の画像を分類したい場合は？
the classification task should be pretty simple.
分類タスクはとても簡単に思えます
So what if we had images of a dog and images of a mop?
犬の画像とモップの画像はどうでしょうか
This should be really easy to classify, right?
分類するのはとても簡単ですよね
The dog is living and breathing.
犬は生きていて呼吸します
The mop has no eyes, nose or mouth.
モップには目 鼻 口がありません
So this should be a relatively easy classification task.
ですから比較的簡単な分類になるはずです
But you'll find that this is actually pretty difficult.
でも実際には とても難しいことに 気付くでしょう
Here we have four photos of sheep dogs and four photos of mops,
シープドッグの写真4枚と
and it's kind of hard even for the human eye to distinguish between the two.
犬とモップを見分けるのは 人間の目でも難しいです
So you get the idea, we don't want to write specific code to
このように 可能性のある すべての特徴を見分けるために
identify every possible type of thing we might see in our images.
個別にコードを書くことは避けたいですよね
Instead, we want to write code that will find these rules for us.
代わりに これらの規則を見つけてくれる コードを書きたいと思うでしょう
We might not just have images.
画像だけでなく 他の種類の 非構造化データも分類したいです
So what I want to talk about today is two ways
そこでGoogle Cloudで 皆さんのアプリに機械学習を追加する
On the left-hand side, we have tools to help you build custom machine learning models.
左側は カスタムMLモデルの 構築に役立つツールです
TensorFlow is an open source library provided by the Google Brain team
TensorFlowはGoogle Brainの オープンソースライブラリです
that lets you build and train your own machine learning models using your own data.
自分のデータを使ってMLモデルを作り トレーニングできます
If you want to run TensorFlow models and manage Google infrastructure,
TensorFlowモデルを実行して Googleインフラを管理したい場合は
we have a tool called Cloud machine learning engine to help with that.
Cloud Machine Learning Engine ツールが役立ちます
What I want to focus on today is the right-hand side,
画面の右側に注目してください
and this is what I like to call friendly machine learning.
これらは いわばフレンドリーなMLです
These are a set of pre-trained APIs to give you access to
このトレーニング済みAPIのセットを使えば
I'm going to be talking about each of the APIs in detail along with some live demos.
それぞれのAPIについて ライブデモを交えて詳しく見ていきます